I've got big news for the human brain
organoids you know the tiny human brains
we grow from stem cells and can run
biocomputation on if you thought this
field was moving fast already well
buckle up it's about to get a lot faster
welcome to biocomputation something that
some researchers like to call Cellular
Supremacy final spark a Swiss company
shocked the world when they offered the
tiny human brains as a computation model
that you can pay for the hope is that
these little guys can do something that
silicone never could not just paring
back human logic but creating logic
putting things together in new ways
living and growing 34 different
universities asked final spark for
access to their materials and methods so
that we can learn more about the brain
organoids and they awarded that right to
eight different universities the
computation model works by attaching
eight electrodes to each individual
brain organoid with 16 to a chip they
then exchange electrical signals so they
can tell the brain organoid what to do
and they can receive what it does and
they're reinforced with dopamine and you
can watch them if you really want to but
let's talk about the research each of
the eight universities is going to focus
on a different task around the brain
organoids the University of Michigan for
example is creating a map of the
chemical and electrical prompts that can
get the brain organoid to do task
shifting in essence creating a computer
language specific to them researchers at
Lancaster University leig in Germany are
focusing on tasks that these guys do
better they're better at Creative
Learning for example and they're going
to test them in different areas to
figure out what they're best at and how
they can be applied other universities
are working in the manufacturing process
there's no standard process to make them
and while some Labs like Allison motores
in UC San Diego have figured out ways to
keep them alive for 10 or more months
right now for the average researcher
it's about 100 days final Sparks
facility is currently housing 3,000 of
them but they want to make them more
quickly and hold more but don't worry
the field of biological Computing goes
much farther than just the use of human
brains join me next time and I'll tell
you about it